All right, guys, welcome welcome. Thanks for
joining in today is January 13th?
2023. It's the
start of a new year very excited. We've got our very
first adsrx live training on for
those who can't physically make it here. The
zoom recording will be available a couple
updates on the ad direct side.
We're about like 50% done with the actual
Advanced training course, we had
a ton of like setbacks happen in last
year. We had closed down an agency. We
like reconfigured all of our priorities. And so
we initially wanted to launch it
January 1st, but
we just got behind. So we're looking to get
that out in the next week. We can have aiming to
get it out before the 23rd. So I'm
really excited about it. There's a lot of stuff in
there that you know, I haven't been
able to express on paper.
That I think is going to just level everybody up
things because you know
when you're in an agency, you're just constantly working so you're
not really thinking too much about like training. So
you're just doing the work but this has
been a really really awesome experience for me teaching you
guys the foundations of like the why
behind the work that you're doing and versus
just, you know, doing the work because I think when you
understand the origin and
the reason why you're doing certain things, it makes makes your
job as an editor a lot better or like you become more proficient
smarter as an editor. So I'm
just gonna jump straight into this.
I'm gonna share my screen.
Right here. Okay, cool.
You guys see that?
Well awesome and if there's any issues definitely hit
me up in the chat box. Hoping that
this thing this presentation is only an
hour, but
it's good to it.
so first off happy New Year on
I don't know about you guys, but I feel like 2023 is
just a fresh start for for me and
I feel really good going into this year. Just a lot
of
I would say like old bag that just I feel was
just thrown away. And I feel like I completely new
person and I'm super stoked and I want to just kill
it this year and I hope everybody else.
Has the same ambition but real quick in the
chat just love to hear and quick comments. Like what are your goals for
2023?
Just list off some couple things whether it's
to lose some weight or maybe gain
weight. If you're trying to build muscle, you
know, read more books, whatever the case of
eat less Filipino food. You guys
tell me
I know for me a goal is always to eat less Filipino
food, but I end up eating more of it.
We got right more music Mark says I
agree with that. I think doing more
creative work where you're passionate about is super
super fulfilling and I want to do more
of those types of things as well.
I think you know working, you
know working to do creative work
that is like client focused
is one outlet, but I
believe you know taking the time to do more
creative work that doesn't have any restrictions and
doesn't have any boundaries on I
think is you need to balance that as a creative person.
Otherwise, you're just gonna burn yourself out or
you're not going to be able to kind of like bring in
new fresh ideas because you're you're not feeling up your own cup
so to speak.
Mark says laugh even more than usual. Yeah, definitely got a
lot more dude.
Lose weight from this time
and start investing.
Yes, that's great. It seems
like Kenneth kind of has the same concept here or more money and also save
more on. I don't know what losing weight and investing
have to do with it each other but
important to lose weight because you know
health is important. I think I
want to lose some weight to
Invest invest your money invest your time, too. I feel like
money and time or are synonymous with
each other. So like what you invest your time into will be
a direct reflection of how much money you earn like.
That's what I've learned and what I'm trying to invest my time
into is like building building the
things like my personal brand and building as RX because
these are things that I know I find invest in will actually
provide me a good return.
And those could be a million other things for you guys in terms of like skill sets
or learning different ways to
invest or you know
saving money I think is really important to on I'm
terrible with money, so I can't really talk too much about this.
But my wife is like super she's super
Frugal and like it like
she gets so excited when she saves like 20 bucks on something. I'm just
like okay Tony bucks. All right, but the
other day she saved like 350 bucks on on a
new refrigerator and like it was very exciting
for her.
Adam says more skateboarding be more
athletic like pre-pandemic dude. Just get
out there start skating start sweating. I think that's one
of those things man if you
Your your exercising but you're doing something fun something.
That doesn't feel like exercise. It's like it's a
win-win right there.
At Mark says lose weight. Also, I think that's a comment. I think
we all just want to like be negative weight, you know, like like invisible
because that would be the ideal scenario
where you don't wait anything.
Okay, everyone just put what's your ideal weight? All right,
if you put on some weight, what's your ideal weight? I'll start with mine. So right
now I think I'm sitting at length.
I weighed myself. I was like 189 and that's like really high.
So I think for this year, I want to be 175. That's
that's my ideal way.
Um, all right, so I know this is about ads and
editing so we'll get into that. Um, so for
this call for this particular meeting we're
going to be going over how to be a better editor in 2023.
And in that we're gonna be talking
about ugc and just different ways
to style videos I think is really important.
Going into 2023 like kind of knowing like what is
currently trending things as
an editors need to start shifting
your mindset to start editing different styles
because you know 2017 when the
dropshipping days were very prevalent like those. I've
been beginning to see a lot of changes in
the creative atmosphere and as editors. We
need to be on top of it. We need to just like know what's
the new trend and what's the new style and start implementing those
because that's what people are used
to seeing next. We're going to be going over a brand new
Emoji Library update that I'm really excited to share with you. Some of
you guys already know this but it's gonna save you a ton
of time.
Three we're going to talk about some upcoming templates. They we
have a ton of like new overlays and new social
proof and and new tools that
are going to just make your life easier, which I'm really excited to share
and then at the very end, we'll do some Q&A you guys can ask
me whatever you want. And that's it. So let's get
into how to be a better editor.
All right tip number one get clear on
the objective the demographic the style format and
core USP. All right when I say
this like
I know as an editor. Sometimes you just get really excited for
me at least like and I just want to jump in there and start
editing and because let's say if I
see the footage or I see the concept and I'm
like, oh I can make that easily, you know, and I'll start going in there.
And the next thing you know, a few hours has passed
and I'm like bullying the
edit and come to come to realize
that I either like edited the wrong thing or right I
use the wrong footage or you know, I wasn't in
alignment with the objective so many different
things on so it's almost it's very important to
before you even get into premiere.
Or whatever editing software you're using is to
just take a step back and okay. Let me
make sure that all of these components all these
areas. I feel very confident in so this
is just kind of a baseline. But okay. What
is the product? What is the objective of the ad? Okay.
What is the demographic
that we're trying to serve? What is the video style?
What is the format? And what is
the USP right? I think I could probably add a few more
other columns here, but for the sake of this example.
from keeping a brief because this is actually a video a product
that we shot yesterday or that I shot yesterday and it
is
It is a skincare product. Okay, or
women who have stretch marks? All right, so I'm
gonna use this as the primary example just because it's relevant. Um,
but, you know a lot of the times
as editors, you're not you're not typically shooting the videos
yourself or you're getting a
ton of ugc From Below or whatever
or from your own customers and
You know, you're not you may not necessarily be the creative strategist
or if you are, you know, you'll be able to see from
start start to from start to end what
that idea was and follow it
through all the way to execution. But at least
for econvets our agency, most of our
editors are just on the back end. So they're just
seeing the Ross for the first time on you
know, they see the script but that's the
only context that a lot of you guys will have so
if you're doing freelance too, you know, like, um,
you know, you're getting a gig and like,
okay, we have a ton of footage. Can you make some videos for us?
the problem that I see a lot of the time specially with brands on
and it doesn't matter if you're working under a
brand or you work with many Brands like in
an agency or you do freelance and you know
you
Take on just like one off jobs or whatever.
Those who are giving you the
footage typically like aren't creative directors, you
know, they're not they may not be even super organized. So
they're just gonna throw a bunch of stuff at you
and then expect you to figure it out. I've known
I see this all the time and special people
who come to economics they'll like,
hey, we have a ton of footage like don't drop it
in a Google drive and okay, like can you make something great out
of this like, yeah, but there's a ton of work that
needs to get done before so I just want you guys to be clear like
before you jump into Premiere. What is the objective? What
is the demographic? What is the video style? What is the format? And what
is the USP because you are the last chain of
Defense here. Um, so for example
the objective for this video
Was you know, the client really wants new customers top
of funnel people have never heard of them. All right,
so just knowing what the objective is. Okay,
is this a cold traffic ad is the top of funnel? Okay this ad
is it needs to sell like pretty
hard or at least like it needs to create awareness for the
brand and needs to have a really strong hook because anytime
you're doing any type of cold traffic ad it's the
first time the client or them. Sorry the viewer seeing
this video. So you have to grab their attention. They don't know who
you are. You have to grab attention, right? So that's kind
of the thing with cold traffic ads. You got to have a strong hook and we'll
go into that a little bit next. It's a is a demographic. All
right. So postpartum women are people who have
given birth or people are actually
or women who are about to give birth. So they're pregnant already but
they have stretch marks. Okay. So this product
helps solve that problem. So you
have to kind of like once you understand what the objective
is. Okay, who am I selling to really like, okay.
Are women with stretch marks like what's
their problem? Right and you can really
boil it down to these people are insecure. You know,
there may be ashamed of their body or they want their
body their old body back. Maybe they've tried a bunch
of different things.
That didn't work for them in the past. And so
this product solves that problem.
Next is video style will go into this in actual like
more detail on but what is the video style? I
think this is the key thing that I really want to stress is because
as an editor your your
control really lies in the style that
you edit. Okay, and we'll go
into a lot of different styles and the different combinations
of styles that you could potentially do as an editor. Um,
because this is going to communicate who
you're like it'll communicate
to your audience like a certain type of audience. Okay.
So if you edit the video in a very commercial
format, you know that video is probably
gonna only resonate on with certain people. If you
edit the video in a very elegant way like it's
gonna appeal to like people who like that style
or if you peel it if you do it in a very ugc way,
right? So as an editor, it's almost like you
have to select. Okay, where am
I gonna put my focus? I'm gonna make this very organic looking.
Or am I going to make this very branded looking
or am I going to combine it together? All right, so based
off of what the client showed us.
She because the product itself is.
A very luxurious looking brand very luxurious product itself
and fairly high
of a price point $45. She's like, I want it to be elegant, you
know, but the same time I know if
you just go all branded on video ads like it doesn't
always convert very well. Okay, those are better used
for like middle of funnel or bottom of funnel ads,
but when you're doing top of funnel like
you just want to you just want to throw everything at the wall.
And and so I was like, okay, we'll shoot
elegantly. I will shoot lifestyle, but we'll edit
it in a very you GC format. Okay, and the
next next two things. I think you know you guys understand what format is
it? Is it vertical? Is it square? Is it four by five? Is it
for YouTube shorts? Is it for you? You know
Instagram reels is it or Facebook feed? These are
all different editing styles that as an editor.
I think you should eventually learn how to do or like understand. Okay words
is being placed. How can I edit the video for that placement?
Next is core USB. You know, I'm not
gonna go too much into this because it's all on the website, but I think
one very important thing to understand before editing
is like, okay. What is
the primary result that I'm trying to achieve with this
video? And that is the core unique
selling proposition because we don't need to add every single
benefit to this product in the
video to try to make itself. Our goal is
to just get them to click. Okay, you just
want them to click on the ad as soon as not maybe
not as soon as possible but like a few seconds in
so that they can learn more. Okay, so
The absolute primary USP is
stretch marks. All right, so you want
to highlight that USP as often as possible and
the other USPS or the benefits
and features come later and you can adjust those like once
or twice in the video, but primarily what you want to see is before
and after before and after that, I like Hammer that
in like this is what is trying to solve.
So going into examples. All
right, so I shot this yesterday and I'm actually really happy with how it
turned out. Um, so on the left side, I shot lifestyle
footage. Okay, and I shot this with I don't
know if you guys can see this camera. Oh, you can't see it Olympic Street
X5 shot at 4K 60fps all natural
lighting. Um, that's what
I've seen, you know, in terms of Lifestyle. It's
all natural lighting. That's what you how you achieve that look.
Um, and then on the right side I shot with the iPhone
ugc footage right here, you know,
I think because the one on the right looks more
staged like it almost comes off almost
like you shot it with a nicer camera, but it's actually not the
case. Um, so this right here
I wanted to share with you is an example
of you know converting.
this clip into more of a branded video
and then the same clip converting it into a ugc
video, right? There's a very like it's
the same shot. But for me, at least this is
what the difference is. It's in the titles. Okay,
so and and also the the
transitions you used, right? So this
is a branded video. I can
feels branded it phased in and out, right? Oh like
it's just like very moody. Right and I'm
sure something like this would work but at the
same time
You know if you're doing Quick Cuts.
You throw ugc style captions on their tiktok style
captions, which you can use which you can find in the
ads or X templates. It's like boom now. It
just feels like it belongs more in the feed. Right? Like it looks
way more organic.
Even with the colors and the Emoji like
I think this is something people would probably
be more inclined to feel like it's not an ad
versus this run definitely feels
like an ad not to say it wouldn't convert in any way, but maybe
you would position this video further down
the funnel as like a retargeting ad like
get 10% off here next, you know
bottle or whatever. Okay, so
you guys are seeing that let me
see.
You let me know in the comments if you guys like you guys can see that big
difference, you know, there's a completely different vibe going on.
Here's another example. Okay. So on the
top example, I used lifestyle footage. I used, you know
high quality 4K.
Mirrorless camera and then this one
I use all ugc.
So same vibe.
But shot with an iPhone, right? So it doesn't mean you can't
achieve lifestyle branded videos with just you
know, a nicer camera you can do the same but what
the difference is here is the actual captions themselves
are giving off more of a you know, aesthetic more
branded look on and I also slowed
the the clips down. So I shot this
at 60 FPS so reducing that to 50%
which you know, you're slowing the video things a lot
more like Smooth.
Cooler whatever you want to call it and then
you know you have the ugc version.
And you know, this could be this could pass off
as a real or something. You know, if you you change that captions, like get
your you can have the same text and completely change the
style it'll completely change the perception of
the viewer when viewing this
content one. They're gonna be like Oh, I'm being sold and the next
one. They're like, oh like somebody made this, you know,
somebody just made this video.
So as an editor, it's really
important when to distinguish to use the Branded
style or use the ugc style and I'll
talk about this later. You don't really want to combine both. Okay,
because like the the purpose of each
one one is to create more brand effect to
establish more credibility to make you feel like
you're immersing the brand and the other one just kind of
feels like, you know, it was done organically like
like it's a piece of content that you would consume
on a regular basis from somebody right? This one
feels like it's from the company. This one feels like it's from a person.
Okay, so I want you guys to be to be aware. The reason
why we edit ugc Styles because we want
people to feel like
Oh, this is trustworthy. I've seen videos like this. All right,
everyone getting that.
Cool. So let's move on to tip number
two. Alright, if you're still unclear ask questions
until you are 100% certain. All right,
so like I said jumping into stuff way
too soon without really getting organized and getting clear
on the objective and getting clear on the format and all that. Um,
you're gonna run to a lot of mistakes and I've done
this before um, and
You know and and sometimes the problem
is.
Sometimes even the brand doesn't understand like well the
direction of the video or they don't even understand their
core USB because they haven't necessarily tested
enough. So you're gonna try to
get as much information as possible from them. But
sometimes you can't even get that. So one
of the things that I like to do is I always
I always do my own research. I think you have to always do your own research before
starting a video regardless of
what the script says or regardless of what the
client says or regardless of what the examples are that they
sent you want to be able to like
actually go out there find similar ads that
are in the similar Niche and kind of
like immerse yourself in that world for a
little bit. I always like to think of it like, you know.
And you just have to jump in the pool of that world. Like
just give me all the information let your subconscious just dial
it in and like you'll see things you'll feel things.
You'll see Faith like once you as a
creative, I feel like our brains are very like, I
don't know maybe scatterbrained or like, you know, we taking a
lot of information. So the more that we can expose ourselves.
I think the better that it comes out
in the edit, but if you're just looking at one thing
and one thing only like it's gonna look like
that or like you're not gonna get as much Clarity and
inspiration if you're just like limiting yourself
to one video.
Um so things you can ask. Hey, can you remind me more examples of the
look and feel for this creative? Can you let me know which USP
is the most important so they could this
could be the primary focus for the video one great thing
about this client is that she actually sent over a ton of
examples for me. So I use that as a
basis and I felt like that was enough.
To kind of get a feel for the video, but
sometimes you know, you don't have those examples. So you have
to kind of do your some digging yourself. All right, and there
should be a collaborative process in all of this, you
know, you shouldn't just like take a video and then just like jump in and then
just start editing it you want to make sure like you're on the
same page like alignment is key always on the
creative. Like that was the big problem when we had a very
very large team was creative alignment just starts to
fizzle out and like take a s*** when there's so
many hands involved in the creative video.
Okay. So one thing that I absolutely hate doing
because myself like I I just like hate wasting
time. Um, there's no bigger ways of time than finishing edit
only find out it was done the wrong way. I have
done this so many times and like I get so frustrated
and I like because I
know you put a lot of energy into finishing and edit
like you have to download the raws, you have to like organize this
footage you have to go and then like you have to go backwards like dude.
I hate that so I I have
learned the hard way to make sure like, I'm 100%
aligned as close as I can before starting
and edit because do titles take time
like, you know, sifting through footage takes time. Everything takes
a ton of time like on average I'd say
like an editor should be able to get like one to two
like solid pieces of content a day, you know, like realistically
within an eight hour period like, you know,
you're only editing for probably like four four to
five and the rest maybe you're doing other stuff.
distracted you know, so it's like
That's the thing. You want to you want to be as efficient as
possible.
and you can you can cut Corners by like
Knowing what to focus on versus not, you know versus wasting
your time doing something you didn't really need to do.
so this is one thing that I want to
stress like as an editor and also like for myself who
has worked with like Direct
Media buyers and like when I mess up
or I take
Way too long on an edit. You know, I'm not only just wasting
my time. I'm wasting the clients time and I'm also wasting
the media buyers time. Okay in the media buyers are
the ones who are running the ads. So as an editor everyone's depending on
you to finish the video. Okay, like
this is um, when you're
not touching any of the ads and anything like it doesn't feel
like you're as much of on a like like a
priority basis like oh I need to get this done. But when you
enter the world and like everybody, you know on the
outside is like waiting for the creative.
It's a lot of pressure and and so
you don't want to miss a day like you like when you
miss a day in ad world.
You're losing money, like people, you
know people in the business is losing money. The ads
are costing more, you know, the brand isn't selling
like there's so many.
The whole flow has to constantly be moving and
if there's any delays man, it just like
it screws up a lot of people on the back end. So I've learned
like for me personally.
Not to do so much at a time. You know,
I I would think that I could edit like
You know.
Five like three clients in a week kind of thing, but it
was getting to a point like, oh my gosh. I can't I
can't keep up with this because I'm
I'm just burning myself out. So I'm just be
mindful, you know, and also if you can't get it done obviously
communicate, like that's that's one of those things and don't overextend
yourself like just be real about the
expectations that you can deliver on because
um, you know
Non-creative people I will say like media
buyers or whatever, you know other people who just
like waiting for the the deliverable they'll just
be like, hey, I need it by this time or whatever but not
taking into account like all the
components and pieces it takes to get a
creative made especially as a
creative person at least for me. I have to be inspired like
I have to like I don't like doing work that I'm not inspired.
So or I don't have enough energy or I'm
not like fully rested, you know, like just kind of forcing a
creative to come out comes out really
bad and I'm like, it takes way more effort to do
that. So, you know, it's getting pretty
complex. But I just want you guys be mindful of like your own energy and just
be real it's like hey, I I think tomorrow I'll
be a better day for me to get this Dad and I'll get it done way better quality if
I'm rested and like I'm not trying to hit that crazy deadline,
you know, I mean anyways
I hope that sinks in for some of you because like for me that was always a big
big problem.
Um next yeah. Remember you're the last chain of
Defense get extremely clear and expectations before beginning ask your
creative director your strategist or research yourself. Those are
the primary things I think.
As an editor like you depending on
what your Ambitions are. I know some of you guys want to make more money and that
kind of stuff.
What I see as a potential like
as a way to making more money in a business or in a
company on a team is leveling up your
skill set, um and and taking on more strategic
roles providing more strategy providing
more feedback versus just
an Executor because I was an Executor for
very very long time when I used to build like landing pages
and design landing pages on but I
wasn't coming up with like the strategy or like writing the copy or anything. I was
just really designing but the moment I stepped into
more of a strategic role.
Um is when like you become a person that
is reliable to provide
Solutions and that's where you can
request more money and you can you know,
get paid more like that's that's essentially how you
move up in a company is like how much more responsibility can
you take and how many more problems can you
write provide solutions to?
so
Another thing too. I think these are just general questions. Like you should ask creative
director of the strategist. How do you want this ad to look? What's the vibe of
this ad what's already working for the brand any examples I can
get inspiration from is this more commercial or more ugc
style. These are all little things man. Like I
know.
sometimes it will just work off of one example, but like
whoever is the strategist behind should have
an idea of where this should be
going.
and if it's not and if they don't like let's say it's a client
or like
You know someone who's not creative like you're gonna have
to make that choice, right?
but I think you can make a smarter Choice by doing
your own research and like okay, I can assess that like
if it's you know, if we're selling phones or for selling,
I don't know just looking at stuff around cameras. Like
I'm gonna look at 10 different camera video
ads in different styles and I'm gonna
pick the one that resonates the most with me because I feel
like
This video sold me better so I'm gonna go with that and
it could be anything. Like I don't
think you need to you need to necessarily be interested in
the product in order to make it sell like
For example the belly cream like I'm never going to use that.
But I know when I
see an ad that's very compelling like all I'm like,
oh dude, I want that like it creates the problem without you
even realizing and then you like have the desire for it.
So another thing is like kind of comparing it
to
Other videos out there
that are not as like Mr. Beast, you
know just like washing their videos or just like
very engaging, you know, they're they're just entertaining and I think that you
have to remember at the end of the day your ad
is not just the only video that these
people are watching. You have to understand that the human
I think there's a new statistic like
People watch like nine hours nine hours
of video a week just on their
phones. Okay, like, you know how
much video you're watching on your own
cell phone like you're scrolling through reels you're scrolling through
YouTube You're scrolling through Facebook. You're scrolling through tiktok. And you're
just seeing a ton of s*** like and if
you're ad if you're video doesn't break through
all of the other crazy stuff out there though
the real viral stuff then you know, you're just
gonna get a swipe and then what happens is you're not
gonna like all the working put into that video is gonna
be a complete waste like I think that's the sad part about creative
is if it takes so much resource and
so much time.
But someone who's just on their phone could just be
like swipe don't care over it and it's
like they don't I mean they don't care how much time went
into it. So as a creative like you have
to think that way first, it's like, okay. Well, how am I gonna get
this person's attention and Dad it up.
so
that leads me to my next point.
Study what's working today? Not last
year or the year before that like right
now? Okay. Um, this is
a link to 141 top directive consumer
e-commerce brands that I put together, um,
which I'll link to their Facebook ad profile. So I'll
share that in the slack but
From here, you can see all it's broken
down by Niche. So you've got health and health and
fitness supplement and wellness Beauty and makeup
hygiene food and drink clothing skincare
pet household. So yeah, like
every Niche you can think of
as well as their their Facebook
ad Library. Okay. This is very important because if
you're not actively looking at other
people's ads, like you're just kind
of like you're not growing and you're not exposing yourself to
enough creative because it's almost
like
the way I see, you know these libraries or
these Gallery so to speak is
you know, this is this for me is inspiration. It's like
especially because I I shoot I shoot my own ads. I
have to know what's working out there and I have to
know these different styles where I can learn from because
If I if I just don't like I'm just gonna look like
I I do the same style videos all the time. And as
a creative, like I always want to be I always
want to be improving but I also want to
just stay up to up to date with stuff because like even
a few months ago. I was making certain Style videos and
then one of my partners was like yeah, dude, that's like not
really the thing or um, you know, it's changed
a lot. Like this is the way people are doing it
now and in the game like everybody is
just copying each other. Okay. So like there's
no definitive one way to do anything. Everyone
is just going inspiration from everybody.
So as an editor as a creative,
I feel like it's it's your job to you know, not just
like watch videos for entertainment but
like look at the Styles, like look at that's titles
that they're using. Look at the transitions. Look at
the hook, like look at every little detail. I'll go
into that right there. What's a study for? Okay, you want
to look at?
Hooks like what got your attention you have
to look at that and not just gonna be inundated by
the video like get hypnotized by the video because that's you know
when I'm taking a s*** in the morning and I'm like
scrolling through Facebook.
And some video catches my attention like I immediately become
like a zombie and I get hypnotized and I just end up
wasting like two and a half minutes watching volcanoes on like
I just that that literally happened
the other day and I was like, oh my God, I need to like snap out of this, you
know.
But instead watch it like analytically and like, okay what what
did get my attention because those are things that
you can pull as a resources and editor. And also if you like
create your own videos you you can apply those. What is
the shooting style was it ugc? Was it lifestyle? Was it like
done on a really nice camera was a lighting, you know, like there's
so many of those little components. What is the video style? I
think you know, was it very organic was
it? Is it feel like somebody made it on
their phone versus was it made in a studio titles? I
think this is the biggest thing these days and more and
more, you know automations and more and more.
Companies are like focusing on titles because
it's it just makes a video that much more engaging right
when you have subtitles when you have bullet points
when you have headlines when you have ctas like, um,
it just provides way more context, but you have to
see how it's styled. Right? Like this is
one of those key things that just the titles alone can differentiate
your video from being more professional to
being more ugc to being more drop Shippy and
I'll show those in a little bit. Um, as well as the you know,
you got to look at the pacing, you know, are they cutting every single second or
are they cutting even more? Are they changing
the b-roll are they? Is it one long
thing?
All different things to consider same with the
length. Is it 15 seconds? Is it 20? Is it
30? Is it a minute was engaged for the whole minute. Where
did I lose interest, you know,
you got to ask yourself when I'm reviewing videos. I'm always
asking myself. We're like if I feel bored
if I get bored at any second of
the video, I'm like, okay something right here needs to
change. Okay something right here in this like at the
six second Mark. I'm over it. Okay, what do
we have to do to spice that six second Mark. Do we
need to add another cut? We need to add like a different
title. Do we need to speed it up? Do we need
to
Add a music change. We didn't add an effect. Right? So you have to
literally consider every second of the video as
an opportunity for the viewer to just
completely scroll away. So that's our
job as editors.
Okay, so tip number four be a diverse and
adaptive editor learn as many styles as
you can. Okay, one thing that like I
think all editors have their strengths. All
right, and every editor edits differently,
that's what I've learned is everyone has their own
previous knowledge and previous experience and pretty and Gifts.
You know, like some of our editors are way are
really good at like Graphics. Um, whereas other
editors are amazing and cuts
or you see um, and so
you have to understand like kind of what your core strengths are because like
you edit in the style.
That suits you as as a person. Um,
but I think it's really important to be
able to be adaptive because as
you know, there's so many
different types of videos out there and it's almost like you
want to have a wide breath
of skill sets or I'm sorry,
like different tools that you can use, you know, you don't want
to just use a screwdriver for every single tool or for every single problem, right?
Um, so your job is an editor is to be nimble and agile, but
also like a chameleon that can edit based on
the objective. All right.
Here's a chameleon just it's got
different colors. You know, the whole metaphor is you
want to be a chameleon when it comes to editing but you're gonna have your
core strengths obviously, but it's like, okay. Well I know how to edit I usually
see or I know how to edit a commercial.
I I know enough to build a pool that up.
so
Here are some like typical examples. Obviously. This list could
go way further. But you have commercial videos. You have
that Viral drop Shippy style that um,
you know was very popular in the early ecomm kids
days ugc as well as
organic. So like your reels your YouTube shorts
your tiktok videos. Those are like organic, right? Those are the videos that
people are just making on their phones, but we can you
can replicate that style within Premiere or any editing software
next is branded and elegant like
do you want to give off that very professional? Like Hey, we're you
know, we're Lululemon and you have YouTube and
I think YouTube is its own category, which kind
of combines a little bit of everything in my opinion. I
I feel like YouTube is one
of those things where
You want to put as much effort? All right, depends on
the objective. Like I said, but let's say like YouTube videos
of of creators or posting on
their Channel I've seen, you know, people put a lot of work into
those videos. Um, and it's because it's like it's permanent,
you know, it's there to stay and it's gonna be there for
years or forever and a lot of people may or may not watch
it. So you want to definitely put a lot of time into the post-production
side of things. So let's go over
some of these examples
We have commercial. Okay versus like
viral Drop Shipping, you know,
it's really funny is
This viral Dropship like we shot this video a long time
ago. And I found I just typed in in YouTube Drop Shipping
video ads examples and I came across
this guy's video and like they just ripped our video like it's just
funny. Like I don't I know there's so much content that
we shot over the years that so many drop shippers have just
Taken for themselves and ripped off. You can't keep track of them all
but I just find it really funny. And on the left you have
commercial, right? You have polished it really nice titles. You know,
it's just very clean, you know, we do this style a lot like Amazon Style
videos or like branded videos, but this is just one style
right file drop ship. It looks like some dude
just made it like in India no offense
India or anything but like you didn't pay that much money to get this thing
made is just like Bam Bam Bam.
Not to say that these videos do not work. Okay, any of
these videos word? Um,
it's just a style. Like I feel
like Dropship videos are a little bit more like
they're like less intentional. They're kind of
like thrown together and they're just
fast and like, you know there they just feel
like
Like a like a unpolished As Seen
On TV ad in my opinion?
All right. Next is ugc organic style.
All right, this one on the left. So obviously shot with a
phone but the captions themselves are tiktok
style or you know, your typical real style.
So a lot of rounded Corners, that's what's gonna
you know, people have our used to seeing it. So in their mind, they're
already kind of like pre-- not pre-sold but they're like, oh
this feels this feels natural. I'm gonna watch the whole thing because I'm used on on
an app because the typical consumer isn't watching
ads all day every day as their
main form of content right like an
ad will pop up every like three or so videos or
five so videos that they're watching and
So when your ad like comes in it either
like interrupts the pattern right call that
a pattern interrupt and then they're like engaged to watch it or they watch
it because it looks just like the rest of the videos that
they're watching, you know,
either one is a win but if you go like
if it does neither, you're just gonna get a nice
way. Um, so, you know this branded elegant
feel on the right. They may not position
this ad as a top up funnel ad that
you would run as like cool traffic. Maybe maybe not
I don't know but this could potentially come in
as a retargeting ad because that person already
knows who athletic greens
is right. So they're already pre-interested in
the in in the product. So, you know, the customer just
needs to be sold a little bit more see more content. So that's
kind of my my two cents on
like where to position a branded at. They really
depends on your consumer and I'll talk about this in the
training, but you
different levels of sophistication for each, you
know type of person so it's like the more sophisticated a
person is the more sophisticated your
ad should be in terms of like quality and
copy and
You know just style. It's like walking into
a very nice clothing store. You know,
everything is very neat and you know, very pristine
and very nice Styles versus like going into a
really cheap store where there's like a million people in there.
Just trying to like get like a bunch of shoes for like
really like a discount. It's a chaos, you know,
so like one has very very particular taste.
The other one is just going for for money. And so
as you know, you have to understand who you're
selling to because if you're selling to people who are just like dude, I just
want this because it's a good deal. Like they don't really care. They're not gonna care
so much about like the brand and the imagery and the
captions. There's like, oh this thing looks cool. It's like 20 bucks. Let's
get it versus. Okay, I'm gonna make a decision on this this product
on the right because I like the
style. Like I'm not the style. I like the brand like the message. I like that and what
they're trying to go for as a company.
So yeah, there's two sides of it always so it really
just comes down to who is going to be watching your video, right?
Here's another style like YouTube. Okay, this is
an actual you this is the same YouTube video that I took
that screenshot from over here. But as
I was watching this video like they put a lot of information like
they put a lot of titles in here a lot of 2D animations a lot
of overlays like a lot of backdrops like super cool.
Well done in my opinion and I think like, you
know, if you're editing that type of style like throw
in that style, but you have to kind of look at like
is it worth it for an ad to put in all that
extra work when sometimes dad doesn't even perform and then
it's like oh, well, maybe I shouldn't that or save it
for a different time. So be mindful of how much
time you put into something because like sometimes
it just doesn't even work and that's kind of the thing
that I've learned is like, okay, I put so much time in that maybe I'm just gonna
reduce it by 30% this time in terms of
like the effects and whatnot.
This is another example of an actual YouTube ad and
I've seen like this is more like affiliate style. But I've
seen these ads just crush it and they're very
straightforward. It's just like, you know, split screen
strong hook and then titles
and like kind of like subtitle format.
you know, it really comes down to the copy in YouTube videos
like the story and the hook and the angle so there's not
so heavy on the
excuse me the editing side. So this
just comes down to like understanding. Okay. What where's
the placement? Where's the format? What is the objective? That way
you can determine what the editing style is going to be?
Another thing you can do obviously is to blend and combine Styles,
but I personally will only limit this
to like two different styles. All right, so you
can do things like lifestyle video with you
you see titles or are you you see video with branded titles
or a commercial video and Dropship style.
You can use commercial video footage and like make
a drop still drop ship style bad. We can
use a YouTube video and use ugc titles. Do you see the combination
here? Like you don't want to be like, okay commercial video with like
Three different styles in there like Dropship style and branded and
ugc. It's just like it'll get like super.
Confusing for the person and yeah it
it's not a good look.
Okay, so just as a reiteration on these
tips, oh by the way, guys, I'm just talking shoot
me a comment in the in the chat.
Let me know if you guys are feeling this if this is
This is valuable.
Just give me a yes if it is valuable or
no, and then tell me to shut up.
Everyone's there everyone's listening. It wasn't I
can't see you guys. So I'm just I think you guys are probably asleep.
All right, Kenneth Kenneth gave me two s's, that's that's sick.
Thank you.
Kind of talking out of my assholes. So
I hope you enjoy it. Hope you enjoy that sound. All right,
so sweet. Adam says yes. Yes, let's go.
All right.
Guys, um, I don't think these will ever
change and I can make this list to 10
or 50, but guys number one
focus on your hook most important part to
any freaking video you see on the internet or
at okay focus on your
hook your hook is the absolute most part.
Three to five three to eight seconds. There's a study, you
know recent I think the average
Attention span is eight seconds now. So you
have about eight seconds. All right, but I think
three seconds is probably
more suitable for ads just because it's all no someone knows
it's an ad already. Like you already
have people like I'm not watching an ad like my
wife. She really watches ads because she's like over it.
But um that hook man, if it doesn't
hook, you've lost all of your
work. That's the way I think about it myself. It's like I care so much
about my work and I want other people
to see the work that I do even if it's an advertisement. Um,
so I'm gonna do what I can to keep that attention
because it's like
it's like building.
You know, it's like it's like building something and and for
someone to not appreciate, you know, like I have this desk right here
and it's like if I didn't tell somebody hey, do you check out
my desk? It's so sick. You're gonna love it. Um, you know,
I don't know. This is a bad example, but the point is you put
all this work into it and if you don't get anyone to see it, it's almost
like it's a shame. It's a waste it's a loss and as a
creative like this is your voice. This is your passion. This is
your your gift to be able to share this, you
know your ability to craft a video
which you know, so much of the world can't do and
if you can't get their attention, then the rest
of the videos is just it just gets disappeared like no one
sees it and I think that's like
You know, you should be mindful of that.
Next time you do a video. All right, number two remove all
the fluff get to the point you at the end of the day man, like especially on
social media depending on where the
person is focused like YouTube obviously when you're
on YouTube
even on YouTube actually like get to the point but um
people's minds are not really thinking like
Critically when they're when they're watching videos, they're
not really thinking unless they're actually trying to
research something on YouTube and that's where long-form content
will come very handy like you're learning tutorial your researching
something done it up.
But on social man, you got to get to the point
remove all the fluff because like do anything that
isn't remotely interesting like you're
done you're done like it's brutal the
work the social media world is so brutal every like
almost like every millisecond counts like every point five
second counts.
But if you don't have a strong enough hook, you know the rest
of the video just won't matter in my opinion. But when
you do get them past the hook, boom now,
you've got to keep things really freaking engaging because they
could leave again, you know, most of the time they're not going to
watch that whole video Until unless it's like, you know, Mr. Beast video
like at the very end of this video, I'm gonna show you how I made
a hundred million dollars in five minutes, but you've
got to watch the whole thing. Right? So those videos like
you're not making those videos if you're making ads but the
point is every second needs to be very engaging so it goes back
to okay. What is that core USP that core
unique selling proposition that I want to keep drilling home.
Is it that you know, the stretch mark before and
after like in that person's mind. They're watching like yeah.
Yeah. I mean, you know, you might get them
hooked because of a visual hook of some sort, but then
as they watch the video, they're like and whatever I'm
over it, like if you're showing before and after after
before and after after before and after like, okay, wait a second,
there's something
going on here that I'm interested in learning more about and that's
when they get to click.
All right, and this could be you know, I think for Kenneth,
I think you have a completely different product. You're not showing before and
afters you're showing a lot of like reactions. You
know, I think those are very very powerful and I'll do
that in a different presentation, but I'm gonna be talking about the different types of
hooks and the different types of scroll Stoppers
that you can extract from your own clips. That should be
used as hooks. But yeah reactions, you know,
those are gonna be huge but maybe for you
it's like the USP is okay. Like how does this look in
my home or like quality? Like each video could
pertain to up one particular USP
that will resonate with a certain
audience like you don't have to throw everything into one video
to make it sell. It's like just focus on the person who
the male who loves getting gifts
that loves, you know, manly stuff that wants
to see if it's good quality made in America like, you
know what I mean? Just distill it boil it
down to
one type of one type of Avatar and that
message is going to freaking hit them harder
than like a ton of bricks like
the more precise you can be in your messaging like
that person is gonna feel like they're hurt that
they're understood but if you kind of like do a blanket statement,
Oh this works great for skin.
It's like cool. Okay, like everyone has
skin but if you say thing or if you do things like this
works great for people who tireless who who
have eczema who have used everything without any
results and want a quick fast solution
and without having oily oily
product, you know, like those are things for
me because I've accidentally like, oh, yeah. I want that, you know versus like oh,
this is great for for itchy skin. It's like yeah well,
I don't care. Okay, so moving on.
every second needs to be engaging maximize the
frame use zooms use cut like
lots of cuts take advantage of like, you
know, if you even if you just have one ugc on go over this and their training
focus on their head focus on their hand focus on whatever is
moving, um take like you could
You could cut up one ugc in so
many different ways if you just like zoom in and zoom out and
punch in and and move to the left like.
Take advantage of those keyframes man. Those keyframes are going to be your best
friend and you'll see so many people especially on
YouTube shorts who do like educational stuff. What's his
name? Alex hermosi. If you watch any
of his videos You'll see like he's all the editors
always moving in and out punching in
and out like so many different ways. Um,
but, you know from a video perspective, it's just
one shot. It's just one shot. So as an
editor, you're like you're in there just kind of like
Finding ways to keep this thing engaging even if you have
very little resources, like that's what you can do.
Lastly number five no Dead Space. Okay,
like if there's there's like
a fraction of dead space like cut it man, like sometimes
even the voiceovers these days they overlap. Okay,
so it's like I'm gonna go into like so
my first point is this then my second point is that it's like there's
no breathing room and in this
day and age like that's the speed which people
are consuming content. So if there's any
dead space like you're already, you know,
you're already done. Like I feel like you don't want
any opportunity for the person to bounce. So you have to
keep that momentum train going that attention span of
a goldfish is like you can't
lose that attention. I just can't stress that enough.
All right, so real quick.
Focusing on your hook. Okay. So let's share
an example of a video that I edited for
a client, um where this
after reviewing the the footage all
of their ugc stuff.
This hook stood out to me
the most and I think as an editor on.
It's so important to look over all of your footage
and this is like I think we have a we have a modularized.
Lesson, but I'm going to show you later.
How to look for how to extract Hooks and
different clips that you can use because a
lot of that stuff is gold. Like if
you overlook it, then you're gonna miss out
on a huge opportunity for the brand for the brand for the client because
they're not looking at it in the same lens as
you they're just seeing as oh this person made video. This is kind
of cool as an editor. It's like you're ability to refine. It's
like, okay. No. No, this is a good clip. Like let's use that
later. So let me just show you how to get a buzz without
the hangover. Oh, yes.
I introduced to you three Spirit three
Spirit three spirit. It's delicious.
I didn't think it could be more obsessed with three Spirit
but I am I needed
a quick pick me up and live in her as perfect for that maybe with Botanicals. They
give you a natural butt. So this one's the social like sir,
and it has green tea. It has Lions me tolc some
bee vitamins and it tastes really good calming. The
cup is my favorite made with plants like ashwagandha and Valerian
root that are so relaxing. So because that same benefit as
blind just without the hangover.
Feels like Christmas in a box. They've really
mastered the mixing of adaptogenic herbs to give you that
buzz without the alcohol now that I'm putting good things in
my body as opposed to booze. It gives me that um
that I'm looking for it's delicious. I am super psyched about
mocktails. Now who would have thought I highly recommend three spirits.
All right, cool. I don't think I've shared
that video. I've only shared that with one other here.
But going back to how to
get a buzz without the hangover. Oh, yes.
Okay. So that's
a four second hook right there. And this did extremely
well for the brand because I'm
pretty sure of that hook. So what we did actually
So when we when we do hooks, you know, we'll have one Your
Hooks could be so many different possibilities. It
could be audio. It could be visual. It could
be text overlay. Okay, or it could
be a combination of all of them. So, um,
In this video this example this particular headline
actually one.
But I get a buzz without the head hangover.
I tried to add as many.
I would say like layers to it. All right,
so to get a buzz one. I add an automated voiceover
without the hangover. Oh, I had
it that little sound effect. I added an emoji. I added
a zoom in. Yes. I added a
further zoom in right so it's not just
a clip and a title. It's like I did what
I could to try to maximize that four second
window. So, you know, it was
as engaging as possible granted like sometimes
you don't get Clips like that that are like amazingly like
well like that was so organic right but
It doesn't matter because you can still create the
same type of excitement, you know with with
anything but you have to see that I'm
listening. I'm seeing and I'm
feeling and I'm also like tasting too like
I feel like she she's like, oh there's a curiosity going
on like what is what is this? Like that's the
start of any great ad is the
Curiosity Factor. Okay. Well, what's going
on here? Whoa, what is that? Oh, that looks cool.
Okay. That's what you want to elicit in any
type of Hook.
So moving forward. Okay. So
any questions so far on that before
I move into more of like the the technical
stuff and we're gonna wrap up here pretty soon because
it's already 10:30.
So far so good.
Cool. Alright. So, um,
hope you enjoyed that part. There's a One update
that I really want to share with everybody. I know a
few of you already have this this feature,
but I found a way to create
a library for all of our
emojis that we use or that
we provided because you know emojis are so
They're just so used all the time now, like if you
don't have a database of emojis, like you're just going on Google and
your right clicking right clicking
and saving them. So one
of the additional kind of pain in the ass steps of
having this Emoji pack was I have to go in here.
in my you know, my my drive and then find it
and then click and drag it into my Premiere
right or whatever program you're using so that
was kind of annoying and so with this
Library you're able to actually
It embeds all of the Emojis without
loading them onto your actual timeline because
dragging all of this into your Premiere is
takes so much time, right? I don't know if you've done
it already, but it's just not worth it. It takes so much time. So
when you do it this way, you just click a
link and then you the library's already downloaded and that's
the way for men from here to load. I don't know why it's being slow. Um,
and essentially from there you're able to click you're able
to search for the Emoji drag it onto your
timeline. Okay, and then boom you have the Emoji it
just saves a ton of time. So I'll share with you guys the
link there.
This Futures. Yeah, Adam says
this feature is lit it yeah guys at the
end of the day man as an editor your
Your job is to be faster like faster quicker
smarter more efficient. At least for me.
I'm like I want I want to get this done like I want to get this done fast.
Um, so here's the actual Library.
All right, and I'll share
with you the link in in slack. But
basically you just install this into
into your your Premiere and you
get all these emojis already embedded. So
this is based off of our library and it's
going to save you time. So I'm really excited about that.
Okay, so moving on we have
a ton of different upcoming templates
coming your way. We've been a little slow on getting
them approved. But there is one
update that I want to share with you guys and it is the the
tiktok title update. I believe
Kenneth actually.
You you requested this for the
Twitter.
Or the Twitter template that we have.
Um, but we thought it would be a lot more effective because the
drop-down arrows.
I really wish my Premiere was loading right now. I do not
know why.
It's not it always does this like when I needed
to load like doesn't load it's usually when
I want a presentation. So I apologize. I apologize anyways, so
with these new tiktok titles wish I
could show you instead of having a drop-down Arrow or
drop down of all the different emojis problem was
it was so hard to see which emojis were what you
know, you don't know the names of them and it's limited. You
can't put all the emojis in there at once otherwise
would be this crazy long drop-down menu.
We actually put a placeholder for
an image where the the if you drop the Emoji image into
there. It'll put it in there for you. Okay, and so
with the library combined you can take the
library take an emoji drag it onto
your timeline and then it gets put into your project and then
you take that project. I'm sorry that emoji and then
drag it into your tiktok title. And then boom you
have any Emoji you want in that tiktok
social style? Okay,
and it's it's very effective. I
think you guys are gonna love it.
So lastly, here's some some upcoming
templates, you know, we've got places we've
got like iPhone iPad stuff. We've got a ton
of like social alerts mock overlays
for every single platform more review stuff
handwritten arrows, which I feel like are very very valuable
using all the time percentage off sound on.
This is a new one. I see a lot of times in hooks like turn
on your sound. So these are all like ways to
like to add as hooks most of them.
I think it's just kind of like.
An additional layer of grabbing attention, so we'll share
those when they come out. They're pretty much done.
All right that wraps up the presentation. Thank you guys for watching.
Hope you guys kill it in 2023. So
I'm gonna open up the floor to questions
and I'm gonna stop sharing.
Thanks for thanks for joining. You guys was that was that? Okay.
Do you guys get some value of that?
Oh, yeah, everyone's muted. You guys can unmute yourself
if you want.
Guys, I was talking.
No.
Mark Japanese questions, or can you have
any questions?
I I can
add one thing sure. It's not a question.
It's more of a statement. No, I
I think that was all perfect and
really helpful. One thing that I
would add is just to be like really cognizant of
a narrative for the
whole video.
And stay in true to it. So like
you use all your tricks like John mentioned to
grab the attention keep the
attention and so on but make sure not to lose the purpose of
the video at the same time. So that way everything is
kind of
strengthening everything else. So the purpose strengthens the
the tricks that you're doing that are catchy and the
catchy things go into that too. So it
could be something like the transition that you use
or the text that you use you chose just because
it's catchy looking which is fine. But make
sure that the text that is getting put up is is furthering
whatever the
point of that part of the video is. So if you have like
a
a formula will say to sell
the product whatever it is for that
video, then like three quarters of the way
through wherever you're at. You should still be hitting an important thing right
there and reaffirming the sale or whatever
it is that you're doing. So that's my add-in.
Yeah, I agree. Yeah, the storyline is
so important definitely something.
That's harder to do especially if you
don't have a story like for example that at I
shared with you the three Spirit one. It's just
a bunch of ugc, you know, and it's almost
like this this dumb and so what I
did was I went through every single one and and
they pulled out extracted all the lines that
I feel like could be turned into a story. Um,
you know, you don't want to start with like you still
want to introduce the problem and all these things like but
you have to be very cognizant of like The Logical
order that you're telling the story because you
have to remember like
That you're not going to jump to the end. Like if I'm going to tell you this like
ghost story you want to hear the punchline at the very beginning or are you
know what I mean? Like you keep people engaged but you
don't want to give them information that they don't have like contacts around
I think context is really the key.
I think a lot of the times we like will introduce a product too
soon without introducing the
problem first.
and it's like
I'll just share it's like
You it's a concept called twisting the knife.
and copywriting where
You really want to like hone in on like this thing
or like I'll just use vacate convey as an
example. So like the thing it's like germs are gross and
they're everywhere on your bed and when you
Have germs on your bed. It can lead to this this and that
and bringing your own stuff to a hotel is the
you know, so inconvenient, that's why
we created the vacay Hove, right? So
it's like oh and then you reveal
the product and then it feels a lot more. Yeah connecting emotionally,
you know connecting visually to
like in their own mind they have to kind of
imagine the pain
Okay, fantastic any other questions before we wrap
up today?
All good.
All right, cool guys, I'm gonna wrap up the the call.
Thank you so much for joining in. I hope
you guys took some tips. I'll share all the additional stuff
in the ads or X channels, but appreciate you and
hope you guys Crush. I'll see you guys next week.